

Subhransu Maharana

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Sr. Full Stack Engineer





+91-9886326216



subhransumaharana@gmail.com



https://subhnet.github.io



https://www.linkedin.com/in/smaharana



ABOUT ME

Experienced Full-Stack Engineer with over 9 years of experience in creating, developing, and deploying applications and solutions across a variety of technologies. Presently holding the position of Sr. Application Engineer at Adobe, aiming to utilize vast knowledge in software development, troubleshooting, and project management to benefit an innovative organization.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Application Engineer Adobe

Jun 2019 - Present (5 years 1 months +)

Automated client onboarding to Adobe Analytics, Launch, and Target, reducing consultant
efforts by 90% and standardizing processes across teams.

- Built executive-focused Adobe analytics dashboards and custom web applications for top digital marketing clients, addressing diverse customer needs.
- Designed and recommended architecture for Gen Al-based initiatives, contributing to innovative projects within Adobe.
- Developed and maintained a connector that syncs data between Microsoft Dynamics and Adobe Campaign, enabling seamless synchronization of contacts and custom entities.
- Developed serverless and event-driven applications using Adobe I/O runtime and events, enhancing integration with various Adobe services.
- Streamlined AEM CM deployment with Gulp Scripts, GitHub API, and GitHub Actions, cutting
 down development time significantly.
- Deployed Big Data Pipelines in Spark on AWS Glue, optimizing data processing and scalability.
- Migrated legacy ETL processes from Apache to WFE (Apache Airflow), facilitating higher volume data processing.
- Reprocessed billions of records for data cleansing in Adobe Analytics, improving data quality and reliability.
- Developed and managed big data solutions using Hadoop, PySpark, and AWS Glue, enabling
 efficient processing and analysis of large datasets.
- Performed data engineering tasks, including building and optimizing data pipelines and ETL processes for enhanced data management.
- Mentored junior engineers and conducted code reviews, ensuring adherence to coding standards and best practices.
- Technologies Used:
 - Server Side: Node.js, Java, Python, Docker, AWS, GraphQL, Apache OpenWhisk, PySpark, Kafka. Express.is
 - Client Side: ReactJS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Software Engineer

Fidelity Investments

Mar 2017 - May 2019 (2 years 3 months)

- Responsible for upgrading the codebase to Angular UI and back-end in Java Spring Boot RESTful Services. Developed testable, reusable, and maintainable components/services, integrating RESTful APIs.
- Built a Table Component Framework for the eTax Application, making dynamic content easily customizable and focusing on its stability. It was reused across multiple teams.
- Implemented lazy-loading, leading to an 85% reduction in web app loading time.
- Identified and suggested new technologies and tools for enhancing product value.
- Managed both front-end and back-end development tasks.

Project Engineer

Wipro Technologies

Sep 2014 - Feb 2017 (2 years 6 months)

Bluedart Website Revamp

- Key Contributor in development and implementation of the Bluedart Website Revamp project from build-out testing and integration into the production environment.
- Developed SOAP-based Web Services (bottom-up) which internally consume various third-party vendors and also call Oracle stored procedures.
- Integrated Google Map API with shortest path implementation.



SKILLS

Java | Python | Javascript | Typescript

FRONT END

LANGUAGES

ReactJS | AngularJS (4.4) | HTML | CSS | JQuery | Webpack | npm | Mocha

BACK END

NodeJS | Express | Pandas | Spring | SpringBoot | Serverless Framework | Flask | MySQL | Redis

BIG DATA

Hadoop | Map-Reduce | Spark | PySpark | AWS Glue | Apache Kafka

DEVOPS

AWS-Lambda,EC2,EMR,ECS,Glue CI/CD | Docker | Apache OpenWhisk | Apache Airflow | Github Actions

MISCELLANEOUS SKILLS

GraphQL | Gulp | Git | Tomcat | NGINX | Maven | Oauth | JWT | Babel | Rest API | Adobe I/O | Time Management | Problem Solving | Adaptibility



ACHIEVEMENTS

- AWS Developer Associate (AWS-DVA) view creds
- Azure Fundamentals AZ-900 view creds
- Winner in "Adobe Gen Al Hackathon '23"
- Selected for "Adobe Tech Summit'21"
- "Team of the Quarter" Awarded for contribution in Adobe, 2020
- "Individual Award" Awarded for solving complex framework bugs in Fidelity, 2018.
- "On the Spot Award" Awarded in Fidelity Investments, 2017.



EDUCATION

B.Tech, Computer Science Veer Surendra Sai University of Technology, Burla, Odisha 2010-2014